Would you like to play a video game
where the NPCs are run by brain
organoids? Yes, the tiny human brains
that you can grow in a literal jar if
you want to and can run computation.
Well, that may be a reality very soon.
Some researchers out of Cambridge want
to do just that. I'm also really excited
for this because I have theorized that
brain organoids could be used to give AI
agency. It's very difficult to train an
AI and program it to be able to take on
tasks independently. But brain organoids
are biological and they can be drained
on dopamine. They proposed using CL1,
the first desktop computer that runs on
tiny human brains that cost about
$30,000. Although you can use the
virtual platform, meaning brain organ
162, a chip are rented out and they're
trained inhouse to do your tasks. They
plan to use the Unreal Engine, which is
essentially a software development space
made for video games. They would like to
drop brain organoids in and have them
play even with each other. We have seen
brain organoids play a lot of really
simple games, even inter agent play in
which they engage with each other and
teach each other how to play a game
essentially. But this would take the
idea much further. They would drop
multiple brain organoids into various
games, different types of games, and
watch them play and develop with each
other. There's even the possibility that
if this were done, we might be able to
play with them as brain organoid NPCs.
This would really test the abilities of
brain organoids and see how far they
would go, how much they could develop if
they were given a task like this. And
remember, the limit on how long brain
organoids can be kept alive was
obliterated. These guys kept them alive
for 5 years, and they could have kept
them alive for longer. The trick was
putting them in a medium that supported
the neurons firing. Researchers can put
them together like Legos. They've
figured out how to vascularize them.
We're essentially at the point where we
could make something much more similar
to our brains, and I want to see what
they do when they play video games. I
would like to provide the smallest bit
of caution. Although this is really
exciting, and I personally am really
excited for it, we can't think of them
too anthropomorphically, it's not
exactly cruel. Even the claim that they
were sentient has been hotly debated and
has been considered an irresponsible way
to discuss these things in part because
it's just not helpful. I mean, you can
think of an insect as sentient. It has
the capacity to have an experience, but
we don't really think about harming
insects that much when it comes to
building a semi-scentient blob of human
brain goo. Yeah, that's going to be a
little bit more concerning. So, it's
just not helpful to research to
anthropomorphize these things too much.
But do enjoy knowing that a lot of the
people who work with them
anthropomorphize the hell out of them.
We may have gotten closer to building
something that might be considered truly
intelligent, which is fun. Also, I
definitely want to play video games
where the NPC is a glob of brain goo.
Let me just say that I can't be mean to
NPCs as is, and knowing that a glob of
brain goo might be running them would
make me a bit more cautious. I can
promise you this. If there is even the
slightest chance that you can play a
video game with the gu of brain goo, or
even if the brain goo is playing video
games, I'll probably be the very first
person to tell you.